var quiz = [{"answers": ["shade-grown agriculture.", "constructed coral reefs for tourism", "monoculture timber plantation.", "ecotourism."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "All of the following are examples of reconciliation ecology except:"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "After a disturbance, a forest will always return to its climax vegetation."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "According to a political economy perspective, the best option for dealing with deforestation is to wait and allow the markets to encourage preservation activities."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Purchasing items designated as \u201cfair trade\u201d helps to promote uneven development in the market."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Rates of forestation and deforestation vary around the world, but overall global forest cover is declining."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Deforestation provides an example of the second contradiction of capitalism."}, {"answers": ["further deforestation", "secondary succession", "primary succession", "disturbances"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The forest transition theory says that innovation and substitution of other resources will lead to:"}, {"answers": ["Logging", "Acid rain", "Plantation creation", "Clearing land for agriculture"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a process by which deforestation occurs?"}, {"answers": ["Insect infestations", "Widespread disease", "Windstorms", "Controlled burns"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "All of the following are examples of natural forest disturbance, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Not all forests that should be preserved are preserved.", "Humans are selecting the composition of the world\u2019s forests.", "Forests are selectively preserved.", "Reforestation leads to more trees on the planet."], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "All of the following are concerns regarding reforestation, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["The farmer\u2019s market in Ann Arbor.", "U.S. ownership of the world\u2019s bananas.", "Fair trade sugar from the Caribbean.", "Locally grown shade coffee."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "An example of uneven development regarding deforestation would include:"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Because trees cannot communicate their own interests, humans have to decide what is best for them, and that often includes expressing our own interests."}, {"answers": ["Induced intensification", "All of the choices are correct", "Forest transition theory", "Market response model"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which of the following ideas suggests that scarcity of trees through deforestation will lead to innovation and substitution of other resources so that trees can recover?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Much environmental activism has resulted in cooperation between wealthy environmental interest groups and local people to protect their livelihoods."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "A person with an anthropocentric viewpoint would strongly favor attributing legal rights to trees."}, {"answers": ["Anthropocentric ecology", "Forest transition theory", "Reconciliation ecology", "Succession theory"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "A way to maintain both human activities and ecosystem services is called:"}, {"answers": ["higher than it has ever been.", "about half as much as it ever was.", "almost none.", "about three-fourths of what it once was."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The area of rainforest coverage in Costa Rica is currently:"}, {"answers": ["Trees have been used in recreation, art, defense and even weapons.", "Tree worship has existed throughout history and to modern times.", "Humans use trees for all of these purposes, and many, many more!", "Trees have been used for food, shelter and even travel."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Trees are used by people in all of the following ways, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["climax vegetation", "ecosystem services", "biodiversity", "succession"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Benefits that an organic system creates though its function such as food, clean air or water, energy, and nutrient cycling are known as _______."}, {"answers": ["Assuming that further deforestation may be necessary.", "Assuming that forest recovery is possible in all regions.", "Assuming that the forest will recover to its original condition.", "Assuming that an economic transition will eventually occur to allow reforestation."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "All of the following are limits of the forest transition theory, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["undergo extensification and intensification.", "increase inputs such as fertilizers and pesticides.", "increase the land area under production.", "abandon their fields and look for other work."], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Under capitalist production systems, farmers in areas of agricultural decline are    least likely to"}, {"answers": ["Plantation creation", "Preservation", "Clearing land for agriculture", "Reconciliation ecology"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "All of the following are examples of reforestation efforts, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["the availability of forests in other regions.", "All of the choices are correct.", "economic development as predicted by the forest transition theory.", "the spatial fix."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The recovery of forests in Europe is likely due to"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Forest activism such as the Chipko and rubber trappers\u2019 movements focus as much on the protection of livelihoods as the protection of trees themselves."}, {"answers": ["Market forces", "Trees.", "A combination of trees and humans globally.", "Local communities to protect their livelihood."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "In a ecocentric view regarding trees, whose interests should be protected?"}, {"answers": ["theory of reconciliation ecology", "theory of ecological succession", "forest transition theory", "forest succession theory"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The ______ states that initial development in a region will cause deforestation, but as the economy changes and people migrate out of rural areas the forest will recover."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Reforestation in certain areas often depends on deforestation in other areas."}, {"answers": ["Reconciliation ecology", "Disturbance", "Succession", "Induced intensification"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "An event that permanently or temporarily alters the vegetation in an ecosystem is called a(n):"}, {"answers": ["Plantations contain less biodiversity.", "Plantations protect native plant species from extinction.", "Plantations offer fewer ecosystem services.", "Plantations push organisms out of an ecosystem, potentially causing extinctions."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "All of the following are potential problems with plantations, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["climax vegetation, disturbance, succession", "succession, climax vegetation, disturbance", "disturbance, succession, climax vegetation", "succession, disturbance, climax vegetation"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "In the process of succession, which of the following shows the correct order of succession?"}]

quizCollection['10'] = quiz
